JEFF DEUTSCH

Web Developer & Information Architect

29 Old Beaver Run Road, Lafayette, NJ 08648

Email: jdeutsch5@gmail.com

Phone: 862-268-6192

I am a highly driven web developer with experience in the entire process chain of making web applications and websites, from the Information Architecture strait through to the development stage. Coming from an agile background I am highly adaptable, well rounded, and fast learning. I am proficient with many web languages and technologies, and always look to add more tools to my belt.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficiencies:

- Front end technologies (HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, JavaScript, Jquery)
- Front end frameworks (Bootstrap)
- SASS and LESS css frameworks
- Content Management Systems (Wordpress & Drupal)
- Cross client HTML emails and blasting services (table layouts, inline styling, Mailchimp)
- Adobe CS Suite (Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Information Architecture & IA/wireframing technologies (Omnigraffle, Bootstrap)
- Project management & ticketing software (Basecamp, Redmine, Salesforce)
- Cross browser compatible development & valid code
- Version control software (git & svn)

Strong Knowledge of:

- PHP
- Proper SEO Practices & tracking tools (Google Analytics)

Experience with:

- Symfony2 MVC Framework
- JS Frameworks (Angular, Backbone)
- Excellent Communication & Organizational Skills

EXPERIENCE

Studio LLC Hoboken, NJ

www.studiollc.com

Studio LLC is an agile web / app development agency. Studio's work consists of both internal projects and collaborations with print/media agencies. Studio specializes in Web and Software Development, PHP development, iPhone App Development, Android App Development, Organic SEO, Drupal development, HTML 5 / CSS 3, JavaScript Development, Social Media Apps / Tools, Digital Strategy, LAMP, Information Architecture.

Web Developer September 2012 - Present

- Developed and themed content managed sites in both Wordpress & Drupal.
- Worked with various frameworks and technologies in an agile environment that consisted of managing several projects concurrently.
- Produced the complete Information Architecture on sites including sitemaps, wireframes, user experience / user interface, and user flows.
- Developed cross-client compatible HTML emails for clients like Chase, American Express, Merck.
- Some clients include: SiriusXM, Chobani, Freshpet, Biotrue, Merck, Copaxone, Sedasys, PRPS, Paul Hastings, & Flyer App.

JAGTAG, Inc. / Augme Technologies / Hipcricket

Princeton, NJ

JAGTAG is a start-up angel funded company specializing in mobile advertising. They have developed a system that allows consumers to take a picture of a 2-D matrix code called a JAGTAG so they can receive brand information, coupons, enter contests, etc. JAGTAG is now a division of Augme Technologies.

Mobile Media Manager/Mobile Marketing Tech

September 2010 - September 2012

- Designed, optimized, and maintained mobile marketing campaigns for fortune 500 and many top pharmaceutical companies (Verizon, Guinness, BMW, etc.) creating upwards of 100,000 engagements
- Created mobile media campaigns for several clients that established repeated business of over \$100,000.
- Filled in running operations for several extended durations reporting directly to the VP of product development.
- Assisted the company in going international, expanding into the UK.
- Assisted in the transition from a proprietary 2-D matrix code format to a new QR code format.
- Developed mobile websites that received site views upwards of 35,000.
- Managed the campaign development through the takeover of JAGTAG by Augme Technologies.

Digital Firefly Marketing

Princeton, NJ

www.digitalfireflymarketing.com

Digital Firefly Marketing specializes in digital marketing for websites with emphasis on SEO, Pay-per-click management, Social media marketing, website services and email marketing.

Digital Marketing Consultant

February 2012 - Present

- Generated keyword strategies to improve organic visits
- Developed and wrote blogs to enhance brands' social media presence
- Installed proficient SEO practices site wide
- Generated and installed content to fill out Drupal frameworks

Jefferson Township Municipality

Jefferson, NJ

Jefferson Township is a municipality that administers over the township of Jefferson and three additional boroughs. Over 22,000 people reside under the Jefferson Township Municipality.

IT Administrative Assistant

July 2008 - Aug 2009

- Provided computer associated technical support to several township facilities (municipality, camp, health services)
- Maintained PC hardware, software, and applications.
- Managed over 60 computers and 10 servers.

EDUCATION

The College of New Jersey Bachelor of Arts, Economics

Ewing, NJ Aug 09 – May 11

• NJ Stars 2 Scholarship

Sussex County Community College

Associate of Arts, Liberal Arts

Newton, NJ Sept 07 – May 09

- Graduated with Honors
- NJ Stars Scholarship